Pinaki Raj Email : pinakiraj15@gmail.com

Mobile: +1-564-218-1528

PROFILE

I am a highly motivated and self-driven software engineer with a relentless thirst for knowledge. With approximately 2 years of professional experience, I continuously seek opportunities to refine my skills and stay ahead in the dynamic field of software engineering.

EDUCATION

Aligarh Muslim University - Zakir Hussain College of Engg and Tech

CGPA - 7.56

Bachelors of Technology in Electronic Engineering; (1st Division)

 $August\ 2015-July\ 2019$

Aligarh Muslim University

85%

Senior Secondary School;

August 2013 - August 2015

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

• Programming/Languages: C,C++, Python, Javascript, HTML5

• Technologies: MATLAB, LTSpice, PSpice, ATLAS

EXPERIENCE

Lasersec Pvt. Ltd.

Assistant System Engineer

Noida, Uttar Pradesh

March 2020 - August 2022

- Condot Technologies: Worked and designed the different sets of holograms using the condot software.
- \circ Created an algorithm to run the system without any manual intervention, increasing the efficiency and production by 40%

APTECH Learning

Aligarh, India

Trainee May 2015- July 2015

• C Training: Learnt the basics of C programming and participated in creating small-scale projects using OOPS concept.

PROJECTS

B2B-Multi-Tenant-eCommerce-API

Aligarh, India

Project Member

2021

• Ecommerce API that contains Owner/Admin oriented endpoints as well as End-User oriented endpoints.

Simulation and Analysis of LED usign ATLAS

Aligarh, India

Project Member

2019

 Improvement of quantum efficiencies for InGaN LEDs and discussed about the blue LEDs, their specifications, polarization ,staircase injection effects ,graded well effects and the emission efficiency of InGaN based light emitting diodes.

Health Care Monitoring System For Pregnant Women and Elderly People

Aligarh, India

Organisation Member

2018

• Created a system that interacts with pregnant women and elderly people to monitor their health based on the historical data stored in the database.

Automatic Lighting and Accident Detection System

Aligarh, India

Organisation Member

2018

• This electronic system consists of ultrasonic sensors, LDRs to drive safely in low visibility.

EXTRA CURRICULUM

- Volunteer Work: Volunteered teaching in govt school on weekends for underprivileged children
- Robotics Clubs: Became a member of RoboClub in 2017 and participated in organising different events on robotics.
- Pre Conference Tutorial: Participated in Pre-Conference Tutorial on Advances in Wireless Technology, held at Zakir Husain College of Engg and Technology in 2017.
- Internet of Things: Participated in Internet of Things Workshop organized by Aptron Educational Institution held at Zakir Husain College of Engg and Technology in 2016.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Employee of the quarter in Lasersec Pvt. Ltd: Received the achievement award for extraordinary performance during the second quarter of the year 2021.
- Contributor in Google's Clusterfuzz project: Resolved an open issue about updating the documentation.